Finding Aid for Department of Internal Medicine (University of Michigan) records, 1931-1997
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Topical Files, 1975-1986
  - Neurology, 1976-1977; 1980-1982; 2 folders
    - 1980-1982 (Box 20)
  - Obstetrics/Gynecology, 1975-1979
    - General, 1975-1979
      - 1975-1979, 2 folders (Box 11)
      - 1977 (Box 20)
      - 1979 (Box 20)
    - Affiliation Report Henry Ford Hospital-University of Michigan, 1977 (Box 11)
  - Occupational Medicine, 1977-1978; 2 folders (Box 20)
  - On-line Appointment System, 1979 (Box 11)
  - Ophthalmology, 1977-1978 (Box 11)
  - Otorhinolaryngology, 1977 (Box 11)
  - Parkview/Turner Hospital, 1977-1980 (Box 11)
  - Pathology, 1977-1982; 8 folders
    - 1977-1982, 6 folders (Box 11)
    - 1977 (Box 20)
    - 1979 (Box 20)
  - Patient Attitude Survey, 1979 (Box 12)
  - Pediatrics, 1975-1983; 5 folders (Box 12)
  - Pediatric Associates Medical Service Plan, 1983 (Box 12)
  - Pharmacy, 1981-1983 (Box 12)
  - Physical Medicine, 1975-1980 (Box 12)
  - Physiology
    - 1977-1982 (Box 12)
    - 1977-1979 (Box 20)
  - Postgraduate Medicine--Special Purpose Trainees, 1975-1978 (Box 12)
  - Prison Health, 1976-1979; 3 folders (Box 12)
  - Professional Fee Policy Committee, 1983 (Box 12)
  - Psychiatry, 1975-1983
    - General, 1975-1983; 4 folders (Box 12)
    - Chairmanship Candidates, 1981-1983; 4 folders
      - 1981 (Box 20)
      - 1982 (Box 20)
      - 1983, 2 folders (Box 20)
    - Review Committee Report, 1981 (Box 12)
    - Review Committee Report Appendices, 1981 (Box 12)
  - Quality Assurance Committee, 1975-1983; 3 folders (Box 12)
  - Radiation Therapy, 1982-1983
    - General, 1983 (Box 12)
    - Chairmanship Candidate, 1982 (Box 20)
  - Radiology, 1975-1983; 3 folders
    - 1974-1983, 2 folders (Box 12)
    - 1980-1982 (Box 20)
  - Referring Physician, 1975-1978
    - 1975-1978, 3 folders (Box 12)
    - 1976 (Box 20)
      [SR RESTRICTED until July 1 2051 ]
  - Research, 1975-1979; 2 folders (Box 12)
  - St. Joseph UM Liaison Committee, 1980-1983; 3 folders (Box 12)
  - School of Public Health, 1976-1983; 5 folders
    - 1976-1983, 2 folders (Box 12)
    - 1977 (Box 20)
    - 1979 (Box 20)
    - 1983 (Box 20)
  - Separate Legal Entity Task Force, 1983 (Box 12)
  - Social Work, 1976-1978 (Box 12)
  - Students, 1975-1983
    - General, 1975-1983; 18 folders
      - 1975-1983, 8 folders (Box 12)
      - 1976 (Box 20)
      - 1977, 2 folders (Box 20)
        [SR RESTRICTED until July 1 2052 ]
      - 1978, 2 folders (Box 20)
        [SR RESTRICTED until July 1 2053 ]
      - 1979 (Box 20)
        [SR RESTRICTED until July 1 2054 ]
      - 1980, 2 folders (Box 20)
        [SR RESTRICTED until July 1 2055 ]
      - 1981 (Box 20)
        [SR RESTRICTED until July 1 2056 ]
      - 1982 (Box 20)
        [SR RESTRICTED until July 1 2057 ]
    - NIRMP Placement, 1977-1980; 3 folders
      - 1977-1980, 2 folders (Box 12)
      - 1977 (Box 20)
    - Research, 1977-1978 (Box 20)
    - Research Forum, 1975-1979; 2 folders (Box 20)
    - Research Project, 1976-1978; 3 folders
      - 1976 (Box 20)
      - 1977-1978, 2 folders (Box 12)
    - Surgery Henry Ford Hospital, 1980 (Box 12)
  - Surgery, 1974-1983
    - General, 1974-1983; 6 folders
      - 1974-1983, 5 folders (Box 12)
      - 1982-1983 (Box 20)
    - Response to Ad hoc Emergency Services, 1980 (Box 20)
  - Teaching and Administration Study, 1976-1981; 2 folders (Box 12)
  - Veterans Administration Deans Committee, 1980-1986; 5 folders (Box 13)
  - Vice Provost, 1983 (Box 20)
  - Washtenaw County Ambulance Service, 1981-1982 (Box 13)
  - Washtenaw County Medical Society, 1980-1981; 2 folders (Box 13)
  - Wayne County Liaison Committee, 1979-1984; 2 folders (Box 13)
  - Wayne County General Hospital, 1981 (Box 13)
  - Westland Medical Center, 1984-1985 (Box 13)
- Meeting Minutes, 1974-1985
  Meeting Minutes (1.15 linear feet) are from departmental meetings, meetings of division chiefs and those of house officers. They are from the years 1975 to 1984 and are arranged alphabetically. These minutes contain discussions of day-to-day procedures and policies for the department.
  - 1975-1985
    - Departmental, 1978-1983
      - 1978-1979 (Box 13)
      - 1979-1980 (Box 13)
      - 1981-1982 (Box 13)
      - 1982-1983 (Box 13)
    - Division Chiefs, 1975-1983
      - 1975-1976 (Box 13)
      - 1976-1977 (Box 13)
      - 1977-1978 (Box 13)
      - 1978-1979 (Box 13)
      - 1979-1980 (Box 13)
      - 1980-1981 (Box 13)
      - 1981-1982 (Box 13)
      - 1982-1983, 2 folders (Box 13)
    - House Officers, 1977-1984 (Box 14)
      - 1977-1978 (Box 14)
      - 1978-1979 (Box 14)
      - 1979-1980 (Box 14)
      - 1980-1981 (Box 14)
      - 1981-1982 (Box 14)
      - 1982-1983 (Box 14)
      - 1983-1984 (Box 14)
- Chairman's Files, 1975-1986
  Included in the Chairman's Files (1.25 linear feet) is documentation of Dr. Kelly's professional activities. Kelly's involvement in the medical profession (especially rheumatology) and the influence of this involvement on the Department of Internal Medicine is apparent through the correspondence and memos in this series. The files are arranged alphabetically.
  - (William) Beaumont Hospital, 1986 (Box 14)
  - Correspondence, 1977-1984
    - Frye, Billy, 1982 (Box 21)
    - Frye, Billy, 1984 (Box 14)
    - Gronvall, John, 1977-1984; 3 folders
      - 1977-1984, 2 folders (Box 14)
      - 1977-1980, 1 folders (Box 21)
  - Departmental Review, 1980s (Box 14)
  - Divisions, University of Washington-Seattle, 1985-1986 (Box 14)
  - Duke University, 1969-1981
    - General, 1969-1977 (Box 14)
    - Tenure, 1981 (Box 21)
    - Wyngaarden, James B., 1967 (Box 14)
  - Hospital Services Evaluation Questionnaire, 1986 (Box 14)
  - Inteflex, 1984-1985 (Box 14)
  - Internal Medicine, 1978-1985
    - General, 1978-1982; 2 folders (Box 14)
    - Historical, circa 1985 (Box 14)
  - Intra-faculty Grievance Blue Ribbon Committee, 1981-1982 (Box 21)
  - Professional Activities, 1977-1979 (Box 14)
  - Lesch-Nyhan Syndrome, 1971-1984; 2 folders
    - 1977-1984 (Box 14)
    - 1977-1983 (Box 21)
  - Maddux and Associates, 1983 (Box 14)
  - Main-Kellogg/Turner Hospitals, 1977-1984
    - General, 1977-1983; 2 folders (Box 14)
    - Associate Director Search, 1984 (Box 21)
      [SR RESTRICTED until July 1 2059 ]
    - Patients, 1978 (Box 21)
  - Manuscript Reviews, 1982-1984 (Box 21)
  - M-Care, 1985 (Box 14)
  - Medicaid/Medicare Policy Advisory Panel, 1983 (Box 14)
  - Medical Campus Personnel Office Directory of Services, 1978 (Box 15)
  - Medical Center, 1985
    - Education Workshop, 1985 (Box 15)
    - Research Retreat, 1985 (Box 15)
    - Strategic Planning Retreat, 1985 (Box 15)
  - Medical College of Ohio (Toledo OH), 1979 (Box 15)
  - Medical School, 1980-1984
    - Departmental Data Base Summary Sheets, 1982 (Box 15)
    - Institutional Self-study, 1980-1981 (Box 15)
    - Nuclear Medicine Review Committee, 1984 (Box 21)
  - National Academy of Sciences, 1983 (Box 21)
  - National Institute of Arthritis, Diabetes, and Digestive and Kidney Diseases(NIADDK), 1984-1986
    - General, 1984-1985 (Box 15)
    - Physician Scientist Award, 1986; 2 folders (Box 15)
    - Search Committee, 1984 (Box 21)
  - North Carolina, University of, 1985-1986 (Box 15)
  - Progress Report for the Medical Diagnostic and Treatment Areas, 1984-1985 (Box 15)
  - Sarbach, Douglas, 1980-1983 (Box 15)
  - Smith, James E., 1985 (Box 15)
  - Students, 1982-1985; 4 folders
    - 1982-1985, 3 folders (Box 15)
    - 1982-1985 (Box 21)
      [SR RESTRICTED until July 1 2060 ]
  - Undergraduate Educational Programs (Annual Report), 1985-1986 (Box 15)
  - Zuidema, George, 1984-1986 (Box 15)
- Pollard Medical Research Institute, 1977-1982
  The Pollard Medical Research Institute (.5 linear feet) series documents the development of the Institute within the Department of Internal Medicine. It is a primary example of the development of study and treatment centers developed during Kelly's tenure. The Pollard Medical Research Institute is a multi-disciplinary center investigating cancer, strokes, heart attacks and arthritis.
  - Advisory Committee, 1977-1978 (Box 15)
  - Congratulations, 1978 (Box 15)
  - Correspondence (Initial), 1977 (Box 15)
  - Faculty, circa 1982 (Box 15)
  - General, 1977-1980 (Box 15)
  - (Fred) Hutchinson Cancer Research Center, 1982 (Box 15)
  - (W.K.) Kellogg Foundation, 1979-1982 (Box 15)
  - (Martin J.) Moran Company, 1979 (Box 15)
  - Progress Report Letters, 1979-1982 (Box 15)
  - Research Suggestions, 1979-1981 (Box 15)
- Topical Files, 1990-1996
  The Topical Files (6.0 linear feet) series is arranged alphabetically and largely follows the arrangement of the original accession. Unlike the 1992 accession, files relating to Divisions are interspersed with the rest of the series. The materials in this series reflect Chief Administrator Chris Durovich's activities (such as the Administrator's Retreat, Clinical Departmental Administrators Meetings, DAAD (Division Administrators and Directors) Meetings, Division Chiefs Meetings, Professional Billing, Reimbursement Subcommittee, Redesign Coordinating Group). Managed care was also an important issue during these years, as well as concern with patient satisfaction and quality assurance. Users should be aware that this accession contained no files with titles between the letters H and N, and so there are no files for Divisions such as Infectious Diseases, Medical Genetics, or Nephrology.
  - ABG (Arterial Blood Gas) Correspondence, 1992-1994 (Box 22)
  - Administrators' Retreat, 1993 (Box 22)
  - Allergy Division, 1993-1996 (Box 22)
  - Ambulatory Care Services, 1993-1996 (Box 22)
  - Apache Medical Systems, 1995-1996 (Box 22)
  - Blue Cross Blue Shield, 1995 (Box 22)
  - Blue Cross Blue Shield, Cardiac Care Program, 1995-1997 (Box 22)
  - Briarwood Medical Group, 1991-1996 (Box 22)
  - Cancer Center, 1993-1996 (Box 22)
  - Cardiac Catheterization Lab in MPU (Medical Procedures Unit), 1990-1997; 3 folders (Box 22)
  - Cardiac Services Contracting, 1994 (Box 22)
  - Cardiology Division, 1993-1995; 4 folders (Box 22)
  - Cardiology Division (cont.), 1996 (Box 23)
  - Cardiology Heart Care Program, 1993-1997; 2 folders (Box 23)
  - Cardiology Subpoena: Investigational Devices, 1992-1996 (Box 23)
  - Clinical Departmental Administrators Meetings, 1993-1997; 4 folders (Box 23)
  - Clinical Practice Workgroup, 1993 (Box 23)
  - Congestive Heart Failure Monitoring, 1996-1997 (Box 23)
  - Correspondence, 1992-1995 (Box 23)
  - DAAD (Division Administrators and Directors) Meetings, 1994-1996; 5 folders (Box 23)
  - DAAD (Division Administrators and Directors) Meetings, September-December 1996 (Box 24)
  - Division Chiefs Meetings, 1990-1996; 6 folders (Box 24)
  - DNA Diagnostic Lab, 1993-1994 (Box 24)
  - Endocrinology & Metabolism, 1993-1996 (Box 24)
  - Endocrinology-Morphometric Nerve Biopsy Studies, 1994 (Box 24)
  - Executive Care Program, 1993-1995 (Box 24)
  - FDA Subpoena, 1994-1995 (Box 24)
  - Fundraising, 1992-1993 (Box 24)
  - Gastroenterology Division, 1991-1996; 3 folders (Box 24)
  - General Medical Division, 1992-1994 (Box 24)
  - General Medical Division, 1995-1997 (Box 25)
  - Geriatrics Division, 1993-1997; 2 folders (Box 25)
  - Graduate Medical Education, 1994-1997 (Box 25)
  - HCFA, 1995-1996 (Box 25)
  - Healthquest System, 1993 (Box 25)
  - Hematology/Oncology Division, 1993-1997; 2 folders (Box 25)
  - Home Med, 1993-1997; 5 folders (Box 25)
  - Kellogg Cardiac Centers of Excellence, 1994-1997 (Box 25)
  - Nuclear Medicine, 1993-1997 (Box 25)
  - Oakwood, 1994-1996 (Box 26)
  - Obesity Program, 1992 (Box 26)
  - Occupational Health, 1996-1997 (Box 26)
  - OSHA Bloodborne Pathogen Standard, 1992 (Box 26)
  - Outpatient Activity, 1993-1996 (Box 26)
  - Outpatient Redesign, 1995-1996 (Box 26)
  - Outpatient Satisfaction Survey Results, 1995 (Box 26)
  - Outpatient Services, 1992-1996 (Box 26)
  - Patient Relations, 1992-1997 (Box 26)
  - Planning & Marketing, 1993-1997 (Box 26)
  - Policies, 1993-1997 (Box 26)
  - Pollard Professorship, 1993-1996 (Box 26)
  - Primary Care, 1993-1997; 3 folders (Box 26)
  - Professional Billing, 1993-1994 (Box 26)
  - Pulmonary Division, 1993-1997 (Box 26)
  - Pulmonary Division, Lung Volume Reduction Program, 1996 (Box 26)
  - Pulmonary Division, Asthma-Airways Center, 1994-1995 (Box 26)
  - Quality Assurance, 1993-1995 (Box 26)
  - Redesign Coordinating Group, 1996 (Box 27)
  - Reimbursement Subcommittee, 1993-1995; 2 folders (Box 27)
  - Research, 1993-1998; 2 folders (Box 27)
  - Rheumatology Division, 1991-1997; 2 folders (Box 27)
  - SEMRHC (Southeast Michigan Regional Heart Consortium), 1994-1997 (Box 27)
  - Single Billing Committee, 1994-1995; 2 folders (Box 27)
  - Specialty Network Development, 1995 (Box 27)
  - Structure Work Group, 1993 (Box 27)
  - Teaching Physician Task Force, 1996-1997; 3 folders
- Financial Files, 1991-1996
  The Financial Files (1.0 linear feet) series is arranged alphabetically, beginning with general year folders. This series contains extensive documentation of an application for a Ryan White Grant in 1996. The grant title was "HIV Early Intervention Services," and it was application for a grant under the Ryan White Title III (b) Program administered by the Bureau of Primary Health Care. This was a program funded "to increase primary health services to HIV infected patients" and was intended to assist low-income patients. These two folders contain the entire grant application and associated materials.
  - 1992 (Box 28)
  - 1993 (Box 28)
  - 1994, 2 folders (Box 28)
  - 1995 (Box 28)
  - Budget Package, 1995 (Box 28)
  - 1996, 2 folders (Box 28)
  - All Funds Budget, FY, 1993-1994 (Box 28)
  - Annual Report, FY, 1995 (Box 28)
  - Cost Effectiveness Program (CEP), 1993-1996; 3 folders (Box 28)
  - Divisional Profit/Loss Analysis, 1993-1996 (Box 28)
  - MCARE Historical Profit/Loss Analysis, 1991 (Box 28)
  - Ryan White Grant, 1996; 2 folders (Box 28)